## Carlos K. Martos

(918) 734-6931

carloskmartos@gmail.com https://csharpfiasco.github.io github.com/csharpfiasco

Tulsa, OK 74137

# **Summary:**

I have emphasized people and clients throughout my career. I enjoy learning from my peers and I enjoy teaching junior employees. My background has involved refactoring VB.NET projects into modern solutions. I have experience with Angular (TypeScript) and the Microsoft stack (.NET, C#, TSQL).

### **Skills:**

- Languages: C#/.NET 6 (NET Core), SQL/TSQL, VB/.NET, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Python
- Libraries: Angular, Angular Material UI, ¡Query, Bootstrap
- Software: SQL Server Management Studio, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Django, Tensorflow/Keras, Photoshop, Illustrator, Microsoft Office
- Source control: Git, Github, Azure Devops

#### **Education:**

University of Tulsa

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2017

## **Projects:**

- At QuikTrip, I developed internal ordering systems with technologies such as .NET 6, Angular 15, MSSOL, and SSIS.
- As technical lead at Techsico, I oversaw and worked on the refactor of a legacy **VB.NET** system into a **ReactJS** web app (with **Tailwind** CSS) with a **.NET Core** back end.
- At Spherexx, I developed and maintained a payment gateway using the Square API in **vbScript**.
- As lead developer (three-person team), I built a custom distribution system, including ordering, client management, order management, purchase order, credit, revenue-reporting systems.
- I developed a quick-reporting system in .**NET Core** to streamline report page builds, including Excel exports.

## **Research Experience:**

## University of Tulsa

• Student Researcher

12/2015 - 04/2016

• Research involved utilizing information foraging techniques to better understand how to improve human-information interaction in source code repositories by MATLAB and App Inventor

## Work:

### **OuikTrip**

4705 S 129th E Ave. Tulsa, OK 74134

03/2021-Current

- Software Developer II
- Web development with ASP.NET and Angular
  - o EF Core
  - o OData
  - Swagger/Swashbuckle
  - o xUnit
- ETL development with SSIS
- Database design with SQL Server
- Windows Services with .NET 6

# Carlos K. Martos

(918) 734-6931

<u>carloskmartos@gmail.com</u> <u>https://csharpfiasco.github.io</u> <u>github.com/csharpfiasco</u>

Tulsa, OK 74137

## Techsico

910 S. Hudson Ave. Tulsa, OK 74112

08/2020 - 03/2021

- Technical Lead and Lead Developer
- Hiring manager for development team
- Project management with Jira
- Product architect responsible for the refactor of the enterprise resource planning web app
- Responsible for training of junior developers
- Used Elastic Beanstalk to host .NET Core API and legacy vb.NET application
- Used AWS Amplify to host websites with continuous integration
- Lead developer for React front end and .NET Core back end
- Managed legacy python applications
- Experience with Open ID (OIDC)

## Spherexx

9142 S. Sheridan Rd. Tulsa, OK 74137

09/2017 - 08/2020

- Full Stack Developer
- Build and maintain liquor and cannabis distribution systems
- Sales dashboards
- Custom websites and content management systems